# Abhimanyu Jha

# Software Developer - Liberty Mutual

Boston, MA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Abhimanyu-Jha/09bce971a68910cc

A dedicated and self-motivated Software Engineer with experience as a Developer and a Technology Analyst in a Fortune 500 company. Recent industry experience is primarily in JAVA and SQL. Additional skills include Production Support, Application Maintenance and Testing, Quality Assurance, Research and Analysis. My inquisitive nature and willingness to learn help me in my daily work. Willing to relocate: Anywhere

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Software Developer**

Liberty Mutual - 2015 to Present

- o Responsible for support and maintenance of this application- mainly using SQL and JAVA.
- o Perform daily checks and work on bug fixes and implement changes through a data fix.
- o Participate in release activities and knowledge transfer plans.

## Associate Software Developer/ Software Developer II

Liberty Mutual Group - Boston, MA - 2014 to 2017

- o Ownership of applications called eLibertyQuote and WCeQuote- application maintenance, reporting and data analysis, using JAVA and SQL.
- o Support and maintenance of Risk Control Workstation a commercial insurance application.
- o Successfully reduced average response time on support tickets.
- o Getting cross trained on various technical skills and conduct knowledge transfer between different departments.
- o Responsible for releases and testing for various Commercial insurance applications.

# Software Developer/Data Analyst

Liberty Mutual - 2013 to 2015

- o Integral member of a multi-million project for the Commercial Insurance Underwriting department at Liberty Mutual.
- o The main objective of this project was to develop an application for the organization which would facilitate more efficient audit activities and retire old legacy systems.
- Individual project at Indiana University Bloomington.

Simulating Soccer Physics in Mathematica 2012

- o The main objective of this project was to study the motion of a soccer ball using Mathematica.
- o The scope of the project included studying the trajectory of a soccer ball abiding the laws of gravitation, painting a realistic scenario of how a ball is kicked on a soccer

field, creating a graphics environment with the Player and the Goalkeeper, and also studying the concept of Magnus force.

# Information Technology Analyst/ Software Developer I

Liberty Mutual Group - Boston, MA - 2013 to 2014

- o Integral part of the Commercial Insurance Underwriting team.
- o Lead various data integration and mapping efforts.
- o Act as a link between the IT and business teams.

## Information Technology Intern

Liberty Mutual Group - Indianapolis, IN - 2012 to 2012

- o Gained valuable experience of the Insurance Industry and various types of applications.
- o Worked closely with testing needs related to QA, Regression and Performance Testing.
- o Participated in activities to release code changes to production.

www.linkedin.com/in/abhimanyu9

Boston, MA

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- > Languages: C, C++, Java, SQL, HTML, XML, SQL, PHP.
- > Operating Systems: Windows 98/2000/NT/XP/Vista/7, MS DOS, MacOS, Linux.
- > Database: Informatica, MySQL, IBM DB2 Visualizer, SQL Server, Oracle, MS Access.
- ➤ Tools and Utilities: IBM Rational Application Developer, Eclipse, LaTeX, Mathematica, Dreamweaver, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office, Adobe Photoshop.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters of Science in Computer Science**

Indiana University - Bloomington, IN 2013

## **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering**

Thakur College of Engineering and Technology, University of Mumbai - Mumbai, Maharashtra 2011

**LINKS** 

http://www.linkedin.com/in/abhimanyu9